[{
        "question": "1. What is inheritance?",
        "correctAnswerIndex": 3,
        "options": [
            "a) The process of bundling data with methods",
            "b) The process of converting objects into strings",
            "c) The ability of objects to take multiple forms",
            "d) The mechanism by which a class can be derived from another class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What is method overriding?",
        "correctAnswerIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) The process of creating a new method",
            "b) Redefining a method in the subclass that is already defined in the superclass",
            "c) Deleting a method from a class",
            "d) Renaming a method in a class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What is method overloading?",
        "correctAnswerIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "a) Defining multiple methods with the same name but different parameters",
            "b) Redefining a method in the subclass that is already defined in the superclass",
            "c) Deleting a method from a class",
            "d) Renaming a method in a class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What is encapsulation?",
        "correctAnswerIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "a) The bundling of data with the methods that operate on that data",
            "b) The process of converting objects into strings",
            "c) The inheritance of properties and behaviors from one class to another",
            "d) The ability of objects to take multiple forms"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What is polymorphism?",
        "correctAnswerIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            "a) The process of converting objects into strings",
            "b) The process of bundling data with methods",
            "c) The ability of objects to take multiple forms",
            "d) The inheritance of properties and behaviors from one class to another"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What is a constructor?",
        "correctAnswerIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) A method used for destroying objects",
            "b) A special method used for initializing objects",
            "c) A method used for copying objects",
            "d) A method used for comparing objects"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What is a destructor?",
        "correctAnswerIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            " a) A method used for destroying objects",
            "b) A special method used for initializing objects",
            "c) A method used for copying objects",
            "d) A method used for comparing objects"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What is the 'this' keyword used for in Java?",
        "correctAnswerIndex": 3,
        "options": [
            "a) Referring to the superclass",
            "b) Referring to a static variable",
            "c) Referring to a local variable",
            "d) Referring to the current object"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What is a class in object-oriented programming?",
        "correctAnswerIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            " a) A function",
            "b) A variable",
            "c) A blueprint for creating objects",
            "d) A loop construct"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "10. What is an object in object-oriented programming?",
        "correctAnswerIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            " a) A data type",
            "b) An instance of a class",
            "c) A control structure",
            "d) A built-in function"
        ]
    }]